Guide to the Philip Clark papers, 2001-2004
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Philip Clark papers
2001-2004
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Philip Clark
C0108
0.25 linear ft.; 1 box
The Philip Clark papers contain information related to the American Planning Association conference and awards. Also included is information on Reston and awards Reston won. The collection is in one series titled subject files which is organized in alphabetical order.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Philip Clark on February 9, 2005.
Biographical Information
Philip Clark, fellow of the American Institute of Certified Planners (AICP) and a 30-year resident of Reston, nominated Reston and Robert E. Simon, Jr., for AICP honors in 2002. Reston is a planned community in Northern Virginia. Simon was the founder of Reston, he purchased the land with the proceeds from the sale of Carnegie Hall in New York City in 1961. Construction began in 1963 with the building of Lake Anne. In 1967, Golf Oil Corporation formed a subsidiary, Reston Gulf, Inc., took complete financial and operational control, and put development on the fast track.
Scope and Content
The Philip Clark papers contain information related to the American Planning Association conference and awards. Also included is information on Reston and awards Reston won.
Series one is titled Subject Files. The series contains information from the American Institute of Certified Planners and American Planning Association. The papers are applications for different awards for national conferences. Also included are photographs and brochures from Reston.
Arrangement
Organized into one series.
Series 1: Subject Files, 2001-2004 (Box 1)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives holds many other collections on the history and development of Reston, Virginia, as well as other collections that document United States and international planned communities.
Index Terms
Persons:
Simon, Robert E. (Robert Edward), 1914-
Corporate Names:
American Institute of Certified Planners.; American Planning Association.
Geographical Names:
Reston (Va.)
Subjects:
Housing--Virginia--Reston.; Planned communities--Virginia--Reston.
Contents List
- Series 1: Subject Files, 2001-2004; (1 box)
  The series contains information from American Institute of Certified Planners and American Planning Association. The papers are applications for different awards for national conferences. Also included are photographs and brochures from Reston.
  - American Institute of Certified Planners (AICP) National Historic Planning Landmark Awards Application, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    1.14
  - American Institute of Certified Planners (AICP) National Historic Planning Landmark Awards Application, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    1.12
  - American Institute of Certified Planners (AICP) National Pioneer Awards Application, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    1.13
  - American Planning Association (APA) Awards Winners, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    1.10
  - American Planning Association (APA) National Conference: Workshops and Tours, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Planning Association's National Planning Conference: Calendar, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    1.04
  - Certified Planners-American Institute of Certified Planners, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    1.07
  - Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    1.18
  - Disks (3.5), 2000s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Happy Birthday Bob, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    1.03
  - List of Members, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    1.19
  - Memorandum, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    1.17
  - National Planning Awards Luncheon, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    1.08
  - Photographs, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    1.16
  - Photograph of Robert Simon Jr. Plaque, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Planning Awards, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    1.05
  - Planning and Landmark Awards, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    1.09
  - Planning Landmark Award-Reston, Virginia, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    1.11
  - Planning Landmarkers Planning Pioneers, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    1.02
  - Reston Founders' Day, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    1.06
  - Reston Mobile Handout Materials, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    1.01
  - Reston: The Evolution of an American Original, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Robert E. Simon, Jr., 2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    1.20
  - Work Order, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    1.15